Nathan George

12319 Oak Creek Lane #1703 Fairfax, VA 22033 nathan@paulgeorge.com (703) 881-1028

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

UVA alumnus with 5 years of software development experience. Proficient in C#, F#, Java, Scala, C, C++, Python, TypeScript, and JavaScript, and experience with application development, full stack web development, cloud-based microservices, and database technologies.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer, Carahsoft Technology Corporation

09/2018 - Present

- Maintain and update an internal management tool that displays and processes financial data for sales, marketing, order processing, and other teams. Develop using C#, XAML, and F# with WPF while improving legacy codebase and developing new features.
- Create and maintain a RESTful web API using ASP.NET Core that facilitates cross-platform
 application development and handles logic for accessing and manipulating shared data.
 Implement security measures within the API to protect sensitive financial data using
 Microsoft Active Directory and OAuth.
- Deploy on-premise Kubernetes cluster for hosting high availability web applications and microservices. Define Docker containers and Kubernetes Deployments for each application, and set up automatic builds and deployments within TFS. Develop new services to be cloud-native. Cloud applications utilize Spark for data processing and Kafka for reliable message passing and logging.
- One of three team members given responsibility to review and approve colleagues' pull
 requests. Provide feedback and suggestions for potential issues and ensure that
 colleagues adhere to team style guidelines. Regularly assist other developers with
 complex technical issues. Train new developers in programming best practices and team
 processes.

Software Developer/Cloud Architect, Piedmont Master Gardeners

08/2017 - 05/2018

- Developed a web-based ticketing system as part of a capstone project with six other developers.
- Responsible for processing form data and database management.
- Responsible for AWS network and computing architecture.
- Created a deployable Amazon Machine Image (AMI) for use within the nonprofit arena.

Research Assistant, University of Virginia Department of Computer Science

05/2017 - 12/2017

- Worked with two Department of Computer Science professors to research the history of SSL and TLS.
- Developed a web application designed to teach students how each protocol version works.

Website Developer, University of Virginia Department of Computer Science

01/2017 - 05/2017

- Developed a financial technology website using Django with a team of 3 other students.
- Responsible for database design and all CRUD operations within the application using PostgreSQL.
- Created controllers for file uploads and downloads, user registration and login, and permission logic.

IT Support, Messick's Farm Market

05/2015 - 08/2015, 05/2016 - 08/2016

- Set up and maintained point of sale and credit card systems and database for a family-owned, specialty farm market.
- Responsible for keeping the system running and updated with latest database fixes and software updates. Provided on call 24/7 support as needed.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Applications

Git and GitHub, TFS, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, SQL Server Management Studio, Eclipse, PyCharm, MySQL, Travis CI, MS Office Suite

Cloud Technologies and Platforms

Kubernetes, Docker, Digital Ocean, Amazon Web Services, Heroku

Operating Systems

Linux, Windows

Languages

C#, F#, SQL, TypeScript, JavaScript, Scala, Java, Python, C, C++, Bash, HTML

EDUCATION

BS, Computer Science, Minor: Applied Mathematics, University of Virginia, May 2018 GPA: 3.274

AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

UVA Engineering Dean's List – Fall 2014, Fall 2015, Spring 2016, Spring 2017 National Merit Scholar Commendation – 2013